Executive Producer : Juzo Itami
An Itami Productions production
Nobuko Miyamoto
Shingo Yamashiro
Ichiro Furudate Fukumi Kuroda NOKKO ( Rebecca )
Juzo Itami
Cinematography : Yonezo Maeda Lighting : Akio Katsura Art Direction : Shuji Nakamura
Special Effects by Dick Smith
Music : Masaya Matsuura Sound : Osamu Onodera Film Editing : Akira Suzuki
Producer : Yasushi Tamaoki Producer : Seigo Hosogoe
Written and Directed by Kiyoshi Kurosawa
Daddy 's taking so long . He must be having trouble .
Hey , Akiko . Maybe you should go and help him out .
It 'll be alright . These kind of things take time .
No matter how much you beg ... It doesn 't matter .
Lfit 's impossible ... then it 's impossible .
I understand your situation ... but please ...
As I already explained ... the entire place is closed up .
Mamiya Mansion is off-limits ... It 's prohibited ...
Whether you 're from a TV station or not ... there 's no exception .
Listen ... In that mansion there are drawings by Ichirou Mamiya
The last fresco by Ichirou Mamiya is in that house .
It 's the obligation of the media to expose this legacy ... -
You are too much ! Why don 't you listen to me ?
You think the word " TV " impresses people like us ?
What 's going on here ?
This guy wants to see Mamiya Mansion .
The Mamiya Mansion ? Out of the question
That mansion has been closed for 30 years
What 's their reason for the visit ?
They are a TV crew ... he claims there 's a Mamiya fresco inside .
TV network ?
Yes . He 's doing research on Ichirou Mamiya 's life
It 's part of a documentary on the community .
- Are you from a TV network ? - Yes
And you 're doing a program on the area ? A food and fauna show
A " taste of the community " kind of program ?
- Yes , of course - Excellent ...
Instead of going to Mamiya ...
Why don 't you go to the City Hall and see our huge tree
It 's the biggest tree in Japan ... called 1000 Year Pine .
Well , maybe .
Daddy needs to be more forceful ... he 's no good at this
He always ends up with people saying " no "
I wonder how he ever got to be a producer .
Don 't talk about your father like that .
But it 's the truth
Since my mother died ... he 's been getting worse
Sometimes I feel like a babysitter .
That 's good ... I 'd like you to be my babysitter .
I won 't be your babysitter , Mr. Taguchi .
That 's no good . She 's so cold to me .
You understand ... you must take all the responsibilty for this .
What could happen ?
You know ... the stories about Mamiya Mansion .
- The curse ? - Yes
If so ... it 's a good opportunity to see ifit 's true or not .
What do you mean ?
If they come back safely ...
We have a new venue for tourism
If something bad happens to them ... by supernatural causes ...
Think of the publicity for our community .
Here is the key to Mamiya 's Mansion .
You 're no good at this . We 'll be here til dusk . Let me try it .
Don 't break anything .
Watch out !
It 's fine , fine !
Asuka ... open it .
Go inside .
Won 't it open ?
Shall we go in through a window ?
Won 't it open up ?
- That 's strange . - Maybe it 's the wrong key .
I don 't think so .
Daddy ... you have to push harder .
My contact lens has shifted .
What ?
I 've just entered the Mamiya Mansion
There 's dust everywhere
I smell the mildew in the air
I 'm worried about whether the fresco has been preserved well ...
That 's a weird sound .
Thirty years ago , the genius artist , Ichirou Mamiya , died here
Since then , the Mamiya family had no one take over the house
For 30 years , no one has entered this mansion ...
What is that sound ?
That was close ...
Everyone ... This house is ready to collapse . Be careful , ok
Daddy look you 're covered in dust .
- Oh ? Still ? - I 'll brush it off .
There seems to be a room over there .
It 's here ... -
- The phones aren 't working . - Oh really .
My guess is ... there 's an electric generator in the house .
An electric generator ...
So now ... we 'll start operations
First , we 're going to remove all the dust
Then we 'll see about the condition of the fresco
Artistic renovation is my specialty
I 'll do everything within my power .
Emi ... I made coffee . Would you like some ?
Father ... Miss Akiko is working very hard , take some to her .
That 's right .
Why are you always like that ?
If you hesitate she 'll be taken by someone else .
Lfit 's her ... I wouldn 't mind
It 's time for you to settle down
You 're not going to be young forever .
Why are you laughing ? I won 't stay with you forever
You have to do something with her during this trip
That 's why I came along with you .
What ? You 're so much like your mom .
What did you say ?
You sound so much like your mom .
Too bad ... That 's it ! I 'm going to explore the house .
So you don 't want coffee ?
Not now .
Where 's Emi ?
She 's around ... She 'll be back soon
Since she was a little kid ... she likes to play by herself
She 's always going to be a kid .
You 'd like for her to be a kid forever .
No ... I hope she marries someday
So I can get back to living a single life
There are so many things I want to do .
See that ... what a find this is . Delicate and vivid .
Emi ... where have you been ?
Don 't you have some homework to do ?
Nonsense ... I 'm on summer break
You were the one who convinced me to come along ... " A chance to see the world . "
Hey ... Can you come down here ? There 's something weird .
Here ... another picture has appeared
And here too
Over there as well .
So this dining room is surrounded with murals .
What is this ?
It seems to be a door or something .
Here ... this one seems to be covered in flames .
Dark .
Black .
Maybe trees .
That 's human . Look ... that 's hair .
If so ... then where 's the face ?
Maybe that 's not a hole ... maybe it 's an eye .
What ? An eye ? It 's spooky
Look at this !
It 's a casket .
Too small to be a casket .
Maybe a casket for a baby .
What 's wrong ?
A baby ! Baby !
The baby is burning .
What do you think about this part ?
These are the parts which appeared later ...
They seem to be drawn without an outline draft .
That 's why they seem to be out of proportion .
It 's not logical ... a fresco artist wouldn 't change concept
... in the middle of a production .
Yes ... something seems to be wrong
What happened to him ?
Something must have happened during the work ...
Some kind of traumatic shock ... it influenced his creativity .
That is a believable story ... for someone like Ichirou Mamiya
But what could have happened ?
Let 's see if we can find some evidence in the house .
Stop at once !
Why ?
I am a reporter . And this is my program
I am the one who does the investigation ...
You are here to shoot the footage . This is my production .
Listen , Asuka ... a documentary is produced by everyone involved
This program belongs to all of us : Taguchi shoots it ...
I co-ordinate the activity ... this isn 't just your program .
Wait a minute . Take it easy , Akiko .
Why should I wait ?
We need to make this clear right now .
I 'm sorry . I understand . Go right ahead
I 'm going to explore .
What ? What is this ? It 's dangerous .
I found this in the shed . Isn 't this amazing ?
Why are you acting like this ?
I told you not to mess around with things before I checked .
Hey ... Put that away .
Look out !
Taguchi ... it 's true . Asuka is right
Don 't mess things up in the house .
That 's nice . That colour looks good on you
Are you ready for bed ?
Yes ... It was my mother 's
When I was a little kid ... she always wore this
So when you wear it ... you remember her ?
Not really . Her memory gets dimmer and dimmer
When I try to remember her I only see light ...
It no longer forms her outline .
What does your father say about that ?
He says that 's the cruelty of time in life and
tenderness of the same time .
Those are smart words from your father .
Akiko ...
What ?
Do you ever think about marrying ?
What ? Maybe some day I will .
Why don 't you hurry up and do it .
Emi ... to get married ... I 'd need to find someone to marry .
Akiko ... how about children ? Don 't you want children ?
Akiko ...
What ?
Can I give this to you ? It would fit you .
You can 't do that
It should be worn by Emi
That 's what your mom wants .
Hey ... pick up your clothes . You 're making a mess .
Okay
Akiko is tough ... she won 't take care of you like I do
You must learn to be independent
And look ... dirty socks . Take care of them .
Alright . Alright . You 're such a bitchy woman
I 'd like to see the face of the poor guy who will marry you .
- I 'm going to turn off the light . - Just a minute
- Come on ! Come on ! - Hold on
- I 'm turning it off . - Wait a minute !
Wait ! Wait !
- Ready ! - Ok !
- Good night - Good night !
Asuka ...
You are beautiful .
Give me back my baby .
Calm down ok . Baby ?
I haven 't done anything to you .
Daddy ?
Did you hear ... - ?
Excuse me ...
" Ken 'ichi Yamamura "
What 's wrong ?
I can 't breathe ... Help me
Pull the lever .
No . The lever ... up .
What is that ?
It 's just an amulet
Not the kind you can buy anywhere .
It 's the real deal .
I don 't need it .
No Mr. Yamamura ... you can 't do that .
You know my name ? That 's an honour .
But I can 't charge the person who saved my life .
Thank you very much .
What are you doing with so much gas ?
I 'm using it for our generator .
We 're shooting a TV program at Mamiya Mansion .
Mamiya Mansion ? Wait . Hold on a minute .
Asuka ... get ready .
Taguchi ... just follow her with the camera .
Alright .
Wait . Wait . Let 's use the wheelchair for the camera .
- Emi - Yes ?
Can you get the wheelchair from outside ?
Yes .
Eh ... What 's this thing ?
What 's wrong Emi ?
Let me do it .
Don 't touch it . Don 't !
How come she dug up such a thing ?
- Oh God ... It certainly was a disgusting thing . - I 'm sorry .
I don 't remember doing anything ... It 's very odd
I 'm sorry I troubled you . I truly am . I 'm leaving now .
Asuka !
Wait !
I 'm going to take her to the hospital .
Emi ... please take care of things here .
Alright . But come back soon .
Pack the luggage ... we may have to leave immediately .
Pack your daddy 's too .
Yes
How 's that ? Electric system failure
What ?
Big trouble . Enormous problems . Maybe we 've got another filter .
It just came off ... -
It came offing my hand . How 's Asuka ?
She 's not injured seriously ...
But she hurt her head and we should take some precautions .
But the car is ... -
I 'll go to the gas station and make a phone call .
It 's about a 30 minute walk .
Let me go for you
Not necessary ... You stay here
Just in case something serious happens .
What do you mean by serious ? What could happen ?
Kazuo ... don 't you think something weird is going on ?
Like what ?
I can 't explain it . But yet ... something odd is going on
You know ... like that baby buried over there .
It 's not strange to bury a body near a country home .
Then what about Asuka going crazy like she did ?
Asuka ?
- She 's basically a crazy woman . - Listen ...
I 'm trying to be serious about this
You see ... I can feel something
There is something weird here
If we stay any longer ... something serious will happen .
What ? Do you really believe in things like the curse ?
I 'm just worried about the way things are going for you .
Why are you laughing at that ?
Because it 's funny .
It 's not funny to care about somebody .
I never expected a woman like you to believe in a silly curse
I wonder if you believe in astrology and the occult . Nostradamus , witchcraft , spirits and the rest .
It 's actually a very charming side of you .
None of this is funny
When somebody talks to you seriously , why don 't you listen ?
I 'm saying I admire you .
Well it doesn 't work ... you don 't understand my feelings .
- I understand everything ... - - You do NOT understand feelings
Neither mine nor Emi 's . You don 't know anything about our feelings .
Your feelings ?
Sorry ...
I 'm just a little upset .
Asuka ?
Daddy ... I 'm scared !
- The shadows ! - What happened ?
- What 's wrong ? - The shadows are alive .
Emi !
Oh ! You scared me !
What are you doing here ?
Asuka ...
Asuka
What 's wrong ?
Don 't you feel good ?
Pull yourself together .
Hey Asuka ... We 'll fix the car and go back to Tokyo .
Asuka ...
What is it ?
- Everybody dies . - Eh ?
Everybody dies !
Taguchi !
Taguchi ... where are you ?
Help me .
It 's taking too long ... what 's he doing ?
I 'm going to check on him .
Wait ... don 't leave us alone
We 're scared ... Don 't leave us here .
Well ... let 's go together .
What now ?
Who did such a thing ? Did you ?
- Who are you ? - Come here
Look ... do you know what this is ?
It protects from the curse .
The curse ?
You destroyed it .
Not me ...
- I didn 't touch it . - Listen , Mr. Yamamura ...
We know nothing about that .
Aki ... do you know this man ?
Yes , it 's Mr Yamamura from the gas station .
- Are you her husband ? - No
Understand this ... you must leave .
You have no right to treat me like this .
Hey
What are you doing here ?
It 's none of your business . You must get out of here
We want to go ... but we can 't .
What do you mean ?
There are two people still in the house
Lets go , Aki ... we have to find Taguchi and Asuka .
Listen ... you better not go inside the house .
- Hey Taguchi - Taguchi
Asuka .
Taguchi .
Kazuo ... we better ask Mr Yamamura to come with us .
Forget about him ... he 's a violent man .
Daddy ... I want to leave here .
Stop ... what are you guys afraid of ?
Taguchi ?
Taguchi !
Taguchi .
Asuka ?
Are you alright ?
Mr Yamamura , what 's going on ?
What 's happening here ?
- Mr Yamamura - Mr Yamamura !
Mom ?
Is that you , mom ?
Emi
Emi ...
- Emi - Emi !
Emi
Daddy ... come on .
Mom ... he 's coming
Now we can live together again .
Daddy ... what are you doing ? Come on in .
Emi ...
Who are you ?
She isn 't your daughter .
What do you mean ?
Emi !
Mr Yamamura !
Idiot ! Do you want to die ? Don 't be such an idiot !
Let go !
Kazuo ! ..
Kazuo ... pull yourself together !
Kazuo ...
What happened ? What 's going on ?
30 years ago
The Mamiya family had a long awaited baby
Ichirou Mamiya was overjoyed
He planned to draw his baby 's growth on these walls
However , his happiness didn 't last very long
One day , Lady Mamiya went to the cellar to turn on the furnace .
What 's wrong with that ?
The baby ... who just started walking
was playing inside the furnace
When she took her child out ... it was too late
The mother also had terrible burns ... she lost an eye
After this incident , surrounding this mansion , babies disappeared
Lady Mamiya was responsible ...
She kidnapped babies and threw them in the furnace .
Why do such a terrible thing ?
She wanted to give playmates to her dead baby
The villagers who discovered the facts ... invaded the mansion
Lady Mamiya was cornered by the villagers
and she threw herself into the furnace .
Lady Mamiya died and Ichirou died a little while later
But he kept drawing until his death
This is the story of the Mamiya Mansion .
We need to look for Emi .
Where is she ?
What 's going on in this mansion right now ?
You woke Lady Mamiya whose soul calmed the shadows
Do you understand what you did ?
In this mansion ... all the shadows and darkness are alive .
Hurry , we must help Emi .
But ... what can we do ?
We must gather all the light ... including flashlights .
Kazuo ... We don 't know anything about this sort of problem
Mr Yamamura ... what should we do ?
Emi is captured by the shadows ... we must destroy them
... with our lighting . We 'll find Emi .
Everybody has tried that
You don 't understand ... that only aggravates them more .
You think so ? Well , your amulet didn 't work either .
When you use light ... then you make new shadows , too
You 'll make shadows everywhere . You have to think ...
Even inside your fist ... there is darkness .
Kazuo .
The necessary thing is concentration
The power of the mind
It 's troublesome to keep your mind strong
Even a big man with a weak brain is useless .
Want a drink ?
No .
Akiko , do you have a child ?
No
Not at all ?
Never
You have no chance then .
Why has she no chance ?
It 's not easy for a woman to beat a mother .
Especially the soul of a mother who lost a child ...
And the soul of a child who lost a mother ... They attract each other .
It won 't be easy to get Emi back .
You think her father can 't do anything ?
Try to squeeze this .
There is no time for jokes
- Emi might die any minute . - I know where your daughter is
It 's not a perfect method ... to enhance the concentration
But it works ... lfl can squeeze this one ... -
Let 's go , Aki ... this is a waste of time ...
I can 't deal with this crap .
Emi is in danger .
Amazing !
Let 's go .
Can I take the light ?
If you 'll feel better ... then do it .
Here ...
Is Emi inside ?
Probably in the furnace ... she 's trapped by Mamiya 's soul
Don 't worry . I 'm going to help save her ...
- Mr Yamamura ! - Mr Yamamura !
The furnace is at the end of the hall .
Aki ! Get the light ! The light !
- Try to keep the light on . - I 'm doing what I can
But the wind is so strong ...
What are you crying about ?
You have a happy past ...
Memories of a happy life .
Please ... give me back my daughter . Emi 's just a child
Emi still needs me . You understand ...
Understand ... you died a long time ago ... long ago .
Aki , Are you alright ? It 's alright , it 's alright
Leave the girl and go back to your own world .
Hold on Emi ... I 'm coming for you .
Mr Yamamura !
Emi !
Run ! The shadows are coming
But , Mr Yamamura ...
Don 't worry about me . Get out quickly .
Emi !
Mr Yamamura !
Let 's go !
- Emi , pull yourself together ! Emi !
We can get out .
We 're saved .
It 's no use !
The shadow is coming ... stay in the light . Don 't move .
It 's no use . It 's getting darker .
Quick ! Break it ...
Kazuo !
I did it !
Aki ...
Aki , are you alright ?
Damn it !
Aki , I 'm going back ...
- But ! - It 's ok
lfEmi comes out , please take her and run
Please ... even ifl don 't come back .
I must go . I have no choice .
I 'll be back .
Aki ...
I wish I had met you before .
Damn it !
Emi !
Power of mind
Please give me the power of mind
Power of mind .
Are you Lady Mamiya ?
Your baby is right here
Don 't hide in the darkness ... show yourself .
Right , I 'll come to see you then .
Not yet !
I can 't ... I can 't let you have this yet ...
Give me back Emi first .
Emi !
This is an hallucination . It must be
That 's it . I 'm being tested .
The power of mind ...
Give the power of mind ... to me ... Please .
Emi !
Give me Emi !
You 're a mother , right ?
Why don 't you understand the mind of a mother who lost a child ?
Emi !
Emi ! Wake up !
This isn 't your child . Why don 't you understand ?
Emi
Emi ! Run ! Quickly !
Akiko !
Emi !
Go back .
Akiko ...
What ?
Where is daddy ?
I 'll tell you later .